<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Felix Thoemmes</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Felix Thoemmes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rounding in the age of statcheck</title>
      <link>/blog/rounding-in-the-age-of-statcheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rounding-in-the-age-of-statcheck/</guid>
      <description>I recently chatted with a colleague whose work was flagged on PubPeer by the statcheck bot that has been scraping the web last year or so. Her reaction - which I believe is pretty typical - was mild annoyance. To her (and I believe many others) it felt a bit pedantic to be flagged what was essentially a rounding error. She feared that such a flag may create a false impression that the work is a “false positive”, and that people jump to conclusions when they see a statcheck error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping exploratory and confirmatory analyses strictly separate</title>
      <link>/blog/keeping-exploratory-and-confirmatory-analyses-strictly-separate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/keeping-exploratory-and-confirmatory-analyses-strictly-separate/</guid>
      <description>Recently Wang et al. published a paper in the Journal of Experimental Psychology on pre-registered analyses and the use of covariates in un-registered, exploratory, post-hoc analyses, specifically in the context of randomized experiments 1.
I am in 100% agreement with the vast majority of what the authors have to say, and also with the general sentiment of the paper, which I summarize as follows:
1.) Pre-register your analyses and report the results of your pre-registration fully</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World (blog roll)</title>
      <link>/blog/hello-world-blog-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hello-world-blog-roll/</guid>
      <description>As Rich Lucas recently said, it seems somewhat anachronistic to start a blog in 2017, but here I am… doing it anyway.
Well, I worry that starting a blog in 2017 is a bit like creating a myspace page in 2010, but here goes: https://t.co/12RevfumqL
&amp;mdash; Rich Lucas (@rlucas11) May 2, 2017 The main reason why I started this blog was probably because I enjoy reading other blogs. So instead of doing the obligatory blog roll section, I will simply write about some blogs that I like.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>